# **Doan Kien**

# Frontend Developer

HighDream softdev0820#3569

## **Profile**

Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web projects for 6+ years. Specializes in ReactJS, Vue and Responsive design. Consistently identifying and providing the technological needs of companies through ingenious innovation. Proficient in developing databases, creating user interfaces, writing and testing codes, troubleshooting simple/complex issues, and implementing new features based on user feedback. Well-versed in proficient programming languages including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Solidity, PHP strong background in web3 projects and customer relations.

### **Professional Experience**

#### Middle Frontend Developer,

11/2020 – 01/2023 | Singapore, Singapore

Orient Software Development Corp.

- Assisted in product development and enhancements of current suite to boost engagement by 15%.
- Increased target audience engagement by 12% by developing web applications with React.js and Vue.js.
- Optimized the codebase by converting class components to functional components using React Hooks and some Redux stores to React context, resulting in the size of the codebase being reduced by 90%.
- Established an interactive and website that guarantees high traffic, page views, and maximum user experience, generating a 25% increase in the company's sales revenue.
- Generated weekly progress updates and presented insights to the design team and project manager; improved project alignment and increased on-time delivery rate of significant projects by 15%.
- Conceptualized and enforced a server that accelerated document generation as well as the searchfunctionality of current websites by 15%.
- Integrated an automated property valuation model fed by machine learning Python data.
- Worked closely with an agile team of 10 members and provided end-to-end solutions for clients.
- Worked with UX/UI design teams to improve existing applications and increase conversion rates by 20%.

#### **Junior Frontend Developer, Noventia**

08/2017 - 10/2019 | Hanoi, Vietnam

- Improved cleanup processes and performance, minimizing downtime by 10%.
- Generated \$50K+ in annual ad revenue as a system administrator of a large network of websites.
- Developed a node.js server to validate membership and track digital badges being used, saving the company \$22.5K.
- Created a compatible, custom client dashboard, reducing support tickets by 45%.
- Designed multiple browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript (React, Redux).

## Frontend Developer Intern, Noventiq

12/2015 - 08/2017 | Hanoi, Vietnam

- Actively engaged in web creative design and development.
- Offered technical support for 10+ existing online products.
- Implemented professional customer service, managing 20+ phone and email requests a day.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks.
- Developed innovative techniques to allow clients to use headless CMS's with technology like Contentful and Google sheets to manage all marketing material.

### Languages

English

Vietnamese

# **Education**

Bachelor of Computer Science (BComSc),

Nanyang Technological University

04/2013 - 03/2018 | Singapore, Singapore